Guide to the Outdoor Advertising Association of America. Nancy Fletcher papers, 1983-2019 RL.11807
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Outdoor Advertising Association of America. Nancy Fletcher papers
1983-2019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Fletcher, Nancy
RL.11807
10.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1891, the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA, now the Out of Home Advertising Association of America) is one of the oldest and largest advertising industry trade organizations in North America. It is headquartered in Washington, D.C. Nancy Fletcher is a lawyer and advertising executive who served as President and CEO of OAAA from 1991-2019. The Nancy Fletcher papers include clippings, correspondence, meeting minutes, newsletters, planning documentation, texts of speeches and presentations and other materials. Topics include highway beautification and other legislation, relations with government regulators, state issues and the transition of the organization to more broadly represent the out of home advertising industry. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History and the Kevin P. Reilly Sr. Outdoor Advertising Archives.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Outdoor Advertising Campaigns; OAAA Administrative Files; Research Reports; Speeches and Presentations.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1891, the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA, now the Out of Home Advertising Association of America) is one of the oldest and largest advertising industry trade organizations in North America. It is headquartered in Washington, D.C. Nancy Fletcher is a lawyer and advertising executive who served as President and CEO of OAAA from 1991-2019.
Nancy Fletcher attended the University of North Dakota and the University of Minnesota (BA, History 1975; MBA 1978) and the Mitchell Hamline School of Law (JD 1981). She worked as an lobbyist for Larkin Hoffman (1975-1978) before joining Naegele Outdoor, Twin Cities, where she held positions of General Counsel, President and General Manager between 1978 and 1991. In 1991 Fletcher was elected President and CEO of OAAA and served from 1991 until her retirement in 2019. She also served as Interim President of Geopath from 2014-2015. Fletcher received a Lifetime Achievement Award from the global out-of-home organization FEPE (now the World Out of Home Organization/WOO) in 2016 and in 2020 was elected to the Board of Directors of Lamar Advertising.
Source: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nancyfletcher
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Access note. Collection contains fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
Access restricted. Portions of the collection closed by donor request until 2029.
Provenance
The Outdoor Advertising Association of America. Nancy Fletcher papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
God Speaks public service advertising campaign records
James H. Fraser papers
Outdoor Advertising Association of America archives.
Collection Overview
The Nancy Fletcher papers include clippings, correspondence, meeting minutes, newsletters, planning documentation, texts of speeches and presentations and other materials. Topics include highway beautification and other legislation, relations with government regulators, state issues and the transition of the organization to more broadly represent the out of home advertising industry.
Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising, Outdoor; Outdoor Advertising Association of America; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Kevin P. Reilly Sr. Outdoor Advertising Archives
- General Files, 1983-2019; 1
  - Clippings, 1998-2012 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Corporate Report Minnesota, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Inside Outdoor, 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - My Turn--OAAA Outdoor Outlook columns compilation, 2001-2011 (Box 1)
  - Nancy Fletcher columns, articles, other writing, 2013-2019; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Publicity and press notices, 1984-1995; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Scenic Byways panel, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Twin Cities Magazine, 1987 (Box 1)
  - William Mitchell Magazine, 1985 (Box 1)
- Outdoor advertising campaigns, 2000-2016; 2
  - Billboard Speaks, 2003-2004; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Billboard Speaks CD-R, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-001)
  - Buzz Bites, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Feel the Real, 2015-2016; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - God Speaks, 2000-2006; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - God Speaks--I'm Talkin' to Kids, 2000 (Box 1)
  - God Speaks--Wesley Theological Seminary, 2000 (Box 1)
  - God Speaks to Kids, 2000 (Box 1)
- OAAA Administrative Files, 1989-2019; 3
  - 1990 Communications Plan (Box 1)
  - 2012-2016 Out of Home Positioning, 2011; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - 2017-2021 Out of Home Positioning, 2016 (Box 1)
  - 2019 Orientation--Communications (Box 1)
  - 2019 Orientation--FOARE (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Foundation for Outdoor Advertising Research and Education
  - 2019 Orientation--Legislation and government affairs (Box 1)
  - 2019 Orientation--Marketing (Box 1)
  - 2019 Orientation--Out of Home (Box 1)
  - 2019 Orientation--Strategic Plan (Box 2)
  - A Comprehensive-Enhancement Public Affairs Plan, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Annual reports, 1992-2019; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Board of Directors, 2001-2007; 21 folders (Box 2)
  - Board of Directors, 2012-2018; 22 folders (Box 8)
    Conditions Governing Access
    This portion of collection closed by donor request until 2029.
  - Brand positioning report, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Budget, 2005-2007; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Budget, 2012-2013; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Executive Committee, 2001-2007; 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee, 2013-2018; 7 folders (Box 8)
  - Focus group transcripts, 1989; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Focus groups, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Focus groups--Consumer Dynamics F1818 Advertising, 2012 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-002)
  - Form 990 (IRS Organization Exemption from Income Tax), 2014-2016 (Box 2)
  - Member survey of principals and General Managers, 1993; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - OAAA Communications Plan, 1990 (Box 3)
  - OAAA Industry Repositioning Project, 2012 (Box 3)
  - OAAA Marketing Orientation, 2014-2019; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - OAAA Millennium Plan, 1999 (Box 3)
  - OAAA Playbook (Katherine Savitt), 1998 (Box 3)
  - OAAA Positioning, 2012; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - OAAA State Issues Handbook, 1998 (Box 3)
  - OAAA Strategic Plan, 1998-2000 (Box 3)
  - Orientation Manual, 2019 (Box 3)
  - Out of Home Advertising: Take Another Look, 2011-2012; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Out of home advertising presentation, 2013 (Box 3)
  - Out of home positioning initiative, 2015 (Box 3)
  - Positioning Outdoor Today, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Post-Convention plan (after Sept. 11), 2001 (Box 3)
  - Rafkin succession project--OAAA Leadership Succession Executive Committee final report, 2018 (Box 3)
  - Top 25 in 25 Years, 2016 (Box 3)
  - Work Plans, 2010-2018; 2 folders (Box 9)
- Research Reports, 1989-2016; 4
  - An Assessment of the Highway Beautification Act's Consistency with American Public Opinion, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Carmichael Lynch presentation, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Focus Group Study of Advertising Professionals, Government Regulators, and Voters in 5 Markets, 1989; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Madison Papers on Outdoor Advertising, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Norman Hecht--Marketing study reports, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Norman Hecht--The State of Out-of-Home Media Research, 1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Peter D. Hart Research Associates, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Research studies--U.S./FEPE, 2016 (Box 4)
  - Squier/Eskew/Knapp, 1991 (Box 4)
  - The Telecommunications Revolution and the Outdoor Advertising Industry, 2001; 2 folders (Box 4)
- Speeches and Presentations, 1992-2019; 5
  - Bear Stearns, 2001-2008; 9 folders (Box 4)
  - Better by Association--Beijing International Outdoor Symposium, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Board presentation, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Boot Camp, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Broadsign interview, 2013 (Box 4)
  - CBS Outdoor, 2002-2017 (Box 4)
  - Clear Channel, 2002-2013; 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Duke University, 2012 (Box 4)
  - Eller Media, 1996-2000; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Eller Media CD-R, approximately 1999 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-003)
  - Fairway, 2003-2013; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Farewell speech, Las Vegas, 2019 (Box 4)
  - FEPE International, 2012-2019; 7 folders (Box 4)
    Federation Europeene de la Publicite Exterieure, now named the World Out of Home Organization (WOO)
  - Fly-In, 1996-2001; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - IBO-USA (Independent Billboard Operators), 2017-2019; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Indiana Association, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Infinity Management Meeting, 2000 (Box 5)
  - International Outdoor Conference, 1996; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Israel/FEPE, 2000; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - FEPE International--Powerpoint, 2000 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-004)
    now named World Out of Home Organization (WOO)
  - Lamar Outdoor, 1996-2014; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Lamar Outdoor--9 Things to Fix, 2000 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-005)
  - Legislative Conference, 2004-2008; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Legislative Conference, 2004-2008; 3 folders (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-006)
  - Louisville Advertising Club, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Madison Advertising Club, 1996-1998 (Box 5)
  - MFL-International Sign Association, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Mile High, Pacific, American Outdoor, 2018 (Box 5)
  - NAHBA (National Association of Highway Beautification Agencies) speech on storm damage (Katrina), 2006 (Box 5)
  - Next Media, 2006 (Box 5)
  - OAAA Convention, 1999-2017; 9 folders (Box 5)
  - OAAA Convention 5:00 PM, 2006 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-007)
  - OAAA Convention 7:30 PM, 2006 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-008)
  - OAAA Convention webinar, 2009 (Box 5)
  - OAAA Legal Forum, 1996 (Box 5)
  - OAAA Operations Seminar, 2002 (Box 5)
  - OAAA Region I, 1996 (Box 5)
  - OAAA Region II, 1996-1998; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - OAAA Region III, 1996-1998; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - OAA Georgia, 2012 (Box 5)
  - OAA Illinois, 2007-2012; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Orlando Advertising Club, 1998; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Outdoor Advertising Today, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Outdoor in Latin America, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Outdoor Systems Inc. (OSI), 1999 (Box 5)
  - Outfront Board, 2015 (Box 5)
  - Peoria Advertising Club, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Positioning Outdoor Today, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Remarks to Legal Seminar, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Revere, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Roundtable presentation, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Sorrento speech, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Speech binder vol.1, 1996-2005 (Box 5)
  - Speech binder vol.1, 1996-2005; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Speech binder vol.2, 1996-2005; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Sunset Strip, 2002 (Box 6)
  - TAB annual conference, 1996-2012; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Tampa Advertising Federation, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Texas speeches, 2001-2004; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - The New Celebrity--Outdoor, 2000 (Box 10, Optical-disc RL11807-OP-009)
  - Titan meeting, 2013 (Box 7)
  - Winter Conference, 1992 (Box 7)
  - YESCO (Young Electric Sign Company), 1997-2017 (Box 7)